

# Achille Salaün

#### Postdoctoral Research Assistant

25 May 1993



Oxford, UK



+336.27.24.11.28



https://achillesalaun.github.io

achille.salaun@eng.ox.ac.uk

# About me –

am a postdoctoral research assistant at the University of Oxford, developing interpretable machine learning models for clinical decision support in kidney transplant offering. More generally, I enjoy working on applied machine learning problems, collaborating with experts, building interpretable tools for them.

# Skills\* -Machine learning Python Matlab **₽TFX**

# Languages' French English Chinese

#### Research interests

Machine learning • Interpretability • Generative models

### Education

2017-2021 PhD in Computational Mathematics Institut Polytechnique de Paris

**ICMLA** 

Title: Alarm prediction in networks via space-time pattern matching

and machine learning

Supervision: François Desbouvries, Anne Bouillard, Marc-Olivier

Buob, Yohan Petetin

Funding: Industrial PhD (CIFRE) between Télécom SudParis

(SAMOVAR) and Nokia Bell Labs

2014-2017 Graduate Engineer (Diplôme d'ingénieur) - Master's degree

Télécom Paris

2015-2017 Télécom Paris' Master specialization in Data Science and Engineering

**EURECOM** 

#### **Publications**

2022	Clinical decision support systems used in transplantat tools for success or an unnecessary gadget?	ion: are they Transplantation
	Wingfield L. R., Salaün A., Khan A., Webb H., Zhu T., Knight S.	
2021	Alarm prediction in networks via space-time pattern ma	tching

and machine learning Thesis

Achille Salaün

2020 Demo: end-to-end root cause analysis of a mobile network

Achille Salaün, Anne Bouillard, Marc-Olivier Buob

2020 DIG-DAG: stockage et recherche de motifs

> dans un flux d'événements Algotel

Anne Bouillard, Marc-Olivier Buob, Achille Salaün, Maxime Raynal

2019 Comparing the modeling powers of RNN and HMM

Achille Salaün, Yohan Petetin, François Desbouvries

Space-time pattern extraction in alarm logs

for network diagnosis MLN

Achille Salaün, Anne Bouillard, Marc-Olivier Buob

2018 Log analysis via space-time pattern matching **CNSM** 

Anne Bouillard, Marc-Olivier Buob, Maxime Raynal, Achille Salaün

### **Projects**

2019

2022-now xamelot 2017-2021 veggie 2020 pybgl

Python 3 library for explainable ML in organ transplant. Python 3 implementation of DIG-DAG related algorithms. contributions to a Python 3 library providing graph tools.

## Experience

2022-Now Postdoctoral Research Assistant University of Oxford

> At the CHI Lab (IBME, University of Oxford), I aim at the creation of an interpretable ML decision support system for kidney transplant offering. This work is done with the collaboration of two clinicians.

2017-2021 PhD in Computational Mathematics Télécom SudParis, Nokia Bell Labs My thesis shows a strong applied component: DIG-DAG related

algorithms have been implemented into a Python 3 module, which has been at the core of a collaboration with Nokia's business units.

2018-2020 Teaching Télécom SudParis

> I supervised lab sessions on Scientific Calculus (Master 1) and Image Segmentation with HMM (Master 2) at Télécom SudParis.

Scales are from 0 (eElementary) to 5 (Expert).